(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-02T23:16:14.810092",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
アニソンナイトフィーバー！
Anison Night Fever!
放て！心に刻んだ夢を
Fire! The dream engraved in my heart...
未来さえ置き去りにして
...leaving even the future behind!
限界など知らない 意味無い
I know no limits, they're meaningless!
この力が
This power...
光散らす
...will scatter the light!
この能力が光散らす その先に遥かな想いを
My ability scatters light, with far-off feelings lying ahead
歩いてきたこの道を 振り返ることしか
If I can do nothing but look back...
出来ないなら...今ここで全てを壊せる
...on this path I've walked, I can destroy everything here and now
暗闇に落ちる街並み 人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
How long can people stand against the town falling into darkness?
加速するその痛みから 誰かをきっと守れるよ
I can surely protect someone from that accelerating pain
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. Right now...
身体中を光の速さで 駆け巡った確かな予感
...a definite premonition raced through my body at the speed of light
掴め！望むものなら残さず 輝ける自分らしさで
Seize it! If it's what you wish for, leave nothing behind with your shining self
信じてるよあの日の誓いを
I believe in the oath of that day
この瞳に光る涙 それさえも強さになるから
Even the tears shining in these eyes will turn into strength
立ち止まると少しだけ 感じる切なさに
When I stop, I won't lie about being...
戸惑う事無いなんて 嘘はつかないよ
...unbothered by the slight sadness I feel
宙に舞うコインが描く 放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by the coin dancing in the air decides destiny
打ち出した答えが今日も 私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I shot out races through my heart again today
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 必ず
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. Surely...
貫いてく途惑うことなく 傷ついても走り続ける
...I will pierce through without hesitation, continuing to run even if hurt
狙え！凛と煌く視線は 狂い無く闇を切り裂く
Aim! The sharp and glittering gaze slices through the darkness without fail
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいい この心が叫ぶ限り 誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
Blow away any hesitation! As long as my heart screams, no one can get in my way
儚く舞う無数の願いは この両手に積もってゆく
Countless wishes dancing fleetingly accumulate in these hands
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは 重く深く切ない記憶
What comes to sight through the sliced darkness is a heavy, deep, painful memory
色褪せてく現実に揺れる 絶望には負けたくない
Swaying in the fading reality, I don't want to lose to despair
私が今私であることを 胸を張って全て誇れる
I can hold my head high and be proud of who I am right now
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search way.
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. 今すぐ
Only my RAILGUN can shoot it. Right now...
身体中を光の速さで 駆け巡った確かな予感
...a definite premonition raced through my body at the speed of light
放て！心に刻んだ夢を 未来さえ置き去りにして
Fire! Leaving even the future behind with the dream engraved in my heart
限界など知らない意味無い この能力が光散らす
I know no limits, they're meaningless! This ability scatters light...
その先に遥かな想いを
...with far-off feelings lying ahead
突然降る夕立 あぁ傘もないや嫌
A sudden evening shower, ah, I have no umbrella, how annoying
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I don't care about the mood of the sky
季節の変わり目の服は 何着りゃいいんだろ
What should I wear during the change of seasons?
春と秋どこいっちゃったんだよ
Where did spring and autumn go?
息が出来ない情報の圧力
The pressure of information makes it hard to breathe
めまいの螺旋だ 私はどこにいる
It's a spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
Even though my breathing is this, this loud
変だね 世界の音が...
It's strange, the sound of the world...
足りない 足りない 誰にも気づかれない
It's not enough, not enough, noticed by no one.
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed with notes like scribbles, unable to make a sound.
「ありのまま」なんて誰に見せるんだ
Who would I show "my true self" to anyway?
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
A fool like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I just pour it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業もなんとなくなんだ
Even changing to Elixir strings is done for no real reason.
欠けた爪を少し触る
I gently touch my chipped fingernail.
半径300mmの体で必死に鳴いてる
Crying out desperately with this 300mm-radius body.
音楽にとっちゃココが地球だな
To music, this must be what Earth is.
空気を握って 空を殴るよ
I clench the air and punch the sky.
何も起きない わたしは無力さ
Nothing happens, I am completely powerless.
だけどその手でこの鉄を弾いたら
But if I play these iron strings with my hands...
何かが変わって見えた
...something seemed to change.
眩しい 眩しい そんなに光るなよ
It's too bright, too bright, don't shine so much.
わたしのダサい影がより色濃くなってしまうだろ
It'll only make my pathetic shadow stand out even more.
なんでこんな熱くなっちゃってんだろ 止まんない
Why am I getting so worked up? I can't stop.
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
A fool like me can only sing.
うるさいんだって 心臓
Shut up, my beating heart!
青い惑星 ひとりぼっち
A lonely, blue planet...
いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
...has listened to so many sounds.
回り続けて数億年
It has kept spinning for hundreds of millions of years.
一瞬でもいいから
Even just for a brief moment...
聴いて 聴けよ
...listen, listen to me!
わたし わたし わたしはここにいる
I am, I am, I am right here!
殴り書きみたいな音 出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed with notes like scribbles, unable to make a sound.
何かになりたい なりたい 何者かでいい
I want to become something, anything at all!
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
A fool like me can only sing.
ぶちまけちゃおうか 星に
Should I just pour it all out to the stars?
また聴いてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for listening again!
聴いてくれるこの環境、とっても嬉しく思います！
I'm so happy to have an environment where you all listen!
いやー、お披露目ライブぶりかもね。もうかなり難しくて、練習頑張ったんでどうだったかな？
Wow, this might be my first time since my debut live. It was so hard, but I practiced so much! How was it?
よかった？嬉しいよ！
Was it good? I'm so happy!
ホロライブ四期生、角巻わため、です！
Hololive 4th generation, Tsunomaki Watame, here!
これみよがしに弾いております。今日でなんと、9歳になりました！
I played it proudly. And today, I turned 9 years old!
お祝いっぱい、ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you for all the celebrations! Thank you so much!
いやー、この日のためにね、もうたくさんたくさん、もう頑張って準備もしてきたので、ぜひ最後まで見て楽しんでほしいなと思います！
Man, I've worked so, so hard and prepared so much for this day, so I hope you'll enjoy watching until the very end!
よろしくベイビー！
Let's go, baby!
ということでね、これはあの、片付けますね。もう使わないのでね。
So, I'm going to put this away. Since I won't be using it anymore.
はい、ちょっと待っててね。よしよし。
Okay, please wait a moment. There we go.
おっこいしょ。このギター、あ、ギターが、おいしょおいしょ。
Heave-ho. This guitar... Oh, the guitar... There we go.
はぁ。わぁ、おっけー。ふぅ。肩凝りになっちまう。よいしょ。
*sighs* Wow, okay. Whew. My shoulders are getting stiff. There we go.
いや、待っててくれてありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for waiting.
今日のハッシュタグはなんと、前代未聞！
Today's hashtag is actually unprecedented!
こちら！角巻わため生誕祭2025なので、
This one! #TsunomakiWatameBirthdayCelebration2025, so...
こちらのハッシュタグをつけて、もうたくさんたくさんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could use this hashtag to post lots and lots of tweets!
今日はアニソンナイトフィーバー、楽しんで、いけますか？！
Are you ready to enjoy Anisong Night Fever today?!
いけますか？！
Are you ready?!
わたは、いけます！！！
Watame is totally ready!!!
では、アニソンナイトフィーバー、いくぞー！！！
Then, Anisong Night Fever, here we go!!!
お？なんだこれは？
Oh? What is this?
こんなのステージに置いてあったら、いけないでしょ？つぎに...
It shouldn't be left on the stage like this, right? Next...
何これ？
What is this?
あ？何なの？誰これ置いたの？あ？
Ah? What is it? Who put this here? Ah?
なんじゃこりゃ？！
What on earth is this?!
このままもう少し歩こう 肩を抱き
Let's walk a little further like this, shoulder to shoulder
消えゆく夢を数え 枯れてく仲間を見た
Counting the vanishing dreams, looking at our withering friends
通い慣れた道に迷い込むこのごろ
Lately, getting lost on a path I'm used to walking
闇がもう一人の自分をつくる
The darkness creates another version of myself
渇いた叫びが くじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A dry scream pierces my disheartened chest
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you to see the world
だれにも出せない答えが僕の中にある
An answer no one can give lies deep inside of me
駆け引きがカギ
Tactics are the key
とどけ fly at higher game
Reach out, fly at a higher game
いくつの悲しみを一緒に越えただろう？
How many sadnesses have we overcome together?
気が済むまで求めたあの日の僕達がいた
We were there on that day, seeking until we were satisfied
時代が巡るなら またどこかで会えるね
If time turns around, we'll meet again somewhere
その時が来るまで諦めない
Until that time comes, I won't give up
冷めてく想いはどうしても否めないけど
I can't deny that my feelings are cooling down, but...
恋に落ちて変わってくのもいいね
...it's nice to fall in love and change
焦らず騒がずあるがままでと願うから
Because I wish to stay as I am without rushing or making a fuss
心に花を咲かそう just take my heart
Let's make a flower bloom in our hearts, just take my heart
渇いた叫びが くじけそうな胸を突き刺す
A dry scream pierces my disheartened chest
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you to see the world
だれにも出せない答えが夢の中にある
An answer no one can give lies deep inside our dreams
僕を信じて
Believe in me
咲かそう just take my heart
Let it bloom, just take my heart
旅路は続いてく
The journey goes on
明日続く坂道の途中で
On the way up the hill that leads to tomorrow,
すれ違う大人達は呟くさ
the adults passing by mutter to themselves...
「愛」とか「夢」とか理想も解るけど
"We understand love, dreams, and ideals, but..."
目の前の現現実(うつつ)はそんなに甘くない、って
"...they say reality in front of us isn't that sweet."
つまずきながらも
Even while stumbling,
転がりながらも
even while rolling along,
カサブタだらけの情熱を忘れたくない
I don't want to forget this passion covered in scabs.
大人になれない僕らの
For us who cannot become adults,
強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
please listen to one of our bluffs.
逃げも隠れもしないから
Since we won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
laugh if you want to laugh.
せめて頼りない僕らの
At least, please don't pluck the bud
自由の芽を摘み取らないで
of our unreliable freedom.
水をあげるその役目を
If you just fulfill the role of watering it,
果たせばいいんだろう？
wouldn't that be enough?
何度も繰り返した失敗とか
Mistakes we've repeated over and over again,
大きく食い違った考えとか
and thoughts that vastly clashed...
僕らの基準はとても不確かで
Our standards are so uncertain.
昨日よりなんとなく歩幅が広くなった
Our stride has somehow gotten wider than yesterday.
背伸びをしながら
While stretching ourselves,
打ちのめされながら
even while being beaten down,
カサブタをちょっとはがすけど 答えは出ない
we peel off our scabs a bit, but there is no answer.
大人になりたい僕らの
For us who want to become adults,
わがままをひとつ聞いてくれ
please listen to one of our selfish desires.
寝ても覚めても縛られる
Please stop the time just a little
時間を少しだけ止めて
that binds us whether we're awake or asleep.
せめて不甲斐ない僕らの
At least, please don't cut off the fruit
自由の実を切り取らないで
of our disappointing freedom.
赤く熟すその時まで
If we can worry until the time it ripens red,
悩めばいいんだろう？
wouldn't that be enough?
大人になれない僕らの
For us who cannot become adults,
強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
please listen to one of our bluffs.
逃げも隠れもしないから
Since we won't run or hide,
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
laugh if you want to laugh.
せめて頼りない僕らの
At least, please don't pluck the bud
自由の芽を摘み取らないで
of our unreliable freedom.
水をあげるその役目を
If you just fulfill the role of watering it,
果たせばいいんだろう？
wouldn't that be enough?
会いたいな 会えないな
I want to see you, but I can't...
切ないな この気持ち
This feeling is so painful.
言えないの 言いたいの
I can't say it, but I want to say it.
チャンス逃してばかり
I'm always letting my chances slip away.
だって だって
Because, because...
翼 広げ 二人で
spreading our wings together,
空をマラソン 夢をユニゾンしたい
I want to run through the sky and harmonize our dreams.
ほら Catch You Catch You
Look! Catch you, catch you...
Catch Me Catch Me 待って
catch me, catch me... wait!
こっちをむいて
Turn this way
スキだと言って決めて
and tell me you love me.
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Yes! Nice to meet you, good to see you, surely...
私の想い あなたのハートに
my feelings will fly right into your heart,
飛んで飛んで飛んでいけ
fly, fly, fly away!
迷わない
I won't hesitate!
たまにね なくなっちゃう
Sometimes, you know, it runs completely flat...
からだのバッテリー
the battery of my body.
あなたの笑顔で
But with your smile,
いつも充電満タン パワー爆発しちゃう
I'm always fully charged and my power explodes!
...はずしちゃえ
...let's throw it off!
おねがい
Please...
まずはお友達から
First, let's start as friends.
笑って 見つめて
With laughs and gazes,
楽しい毎日にしたい
I want to make every day fun.
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, definitely!
運命だって お似合いだって そう
Destiny, they say we're a perfect match, yes!
ナイス Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, surely!
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で
I won't lose to anyone in the world for you,
一番 一番 一番 一番
You are number one, number one, number one...
コ・イ・シ・テ・ル
I'm in love with you!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
Look, Catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, wait!
こっちをむいて
Look this way,
スキだといって そう
And tell me you love me, yes!
ナイス Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, surely!
私の想い あなたのハートに
May my feelings fly to your heart,
飛んで 飛んで 飛んでいけ
Fly, fly, fly away!
迷わない
I won't hesitate!
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, Catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me, definitely!
運命だって お似合いだって そう
Destiny, they say we're a perfect match, yes!
ナイス Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, surely!
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で
I won't lose to anyone in the world for you,
一番 一番 一番 一番
You are number one, number one, number one...
コ・イ・シ・テ・ル
I'm in love with you!
また夢から覚める 濡れた瞼を開ける
Waking up from a dream again, opening my wet eyelids.
狂おしいほど思い残す 遠い日の無力を呪う
Unsatisfied to a maddening degree, cursing my past helplessness.
身を焼かれるような絶望も糧にはなろうか
Would even a body-burning despair serve as nourishment?
憧れに焦がれるまま燃やし続けている
Remaining yearning for my admiration, I keep burning.
キラキラ星屑宿したあなたのeyes
Your eyes harboring sparkling stardust.
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛？
Is it a pitiful, bone-dry lack of love?
全てを孤独から救う眩しい光
A dazzling light that saves everything from loneliness,
僕にだけ落ちる影はあなたのせい？
Is the shadow falling only on me your fault?
致命的な欠落をくれたね
You gave me a fatal deficiency, didn't you?
身勝手な巨星 狂わされた生
A selfish giant star, a life driven mad.
お願い、声を聞かせて、声を聞かせて
Please, let me hear your voice, let me hear your voice.
絡まって歪んでしまった傷さえ
Even the wounds that became tangled and warped...
くれたのはあなただけ、あなただけ
You are the only one who gave them to me, only you.
あぁ、あなただけ、あなただけ
Ah, only you, only you...
お願い、僕を見ていて、僕を見ていて
Please, keep looking at me, keep looking at me.
宿命に刻まれた痛みさえ武器にして\u0000
Using even the pain carved into destiny as a weapon,
いつかの後悔すら照らせるように
So that I can illuminate even some past regret.
あなたがないと生きていけない
Without you, I cannot live.
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
I don't mind sacrificing everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough.
撫でる手を
the hand that caresses it.
この舞台で足掻くことをやめない
I won't stop struggling on this stage
ただ一つのアイに近づきたい
I just want to get closer to that one love
固く定まったこの宿命
This firmly determined destiny
あの星の光から零れた闇
The darkness that spilled from that star's light
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I can't live without you
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
It's fine even if I sacrifice everything
あなたの愛がまだ足らない
Your love is still not enough
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい？
What should I fill the missing pieces with?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
A fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命的、運命的な愛
A fated, fated, fated love
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
An inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
僕を見ていてね
Keep your eyes on me
最愛のファタール！
My beloved Fatal!
You're my fatal.
最愛のファタール
My beloved Fatal
まるで御伽の話
It's just like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
A testament to the end
長すぎる旅路から
From a journey that was far too long,
切り出した一節
a single passage was carved out.
それはかつてこの地に
It tells of the evil
影を落とした悪を
that once cast a shadow over this land,
討ち取りし勇者との
and the hero who defeated it,
短い旅の記憶
a memory of their brief journey.
物語は終わり
The story comes to an end,
勇者は眠りにつく
and the hero goes to his final rest.
穏やかな日常を
Leaving a peaceful daily life
この地に残して保存する
behind in this land.
時の流れは無情に
The merciless flow of time
人を忘れさせる
makes people forget.
そこに生きた軌跡も
Even the footprints left of a life lived there
錆び付いていく
are starting to rust away.
それでも君の
Even so, your...
言葉も願いも勇気も
...words, wishes, and courage...
今も確かに私の中で
...are still certainly alive within me,
生きている
even now.
同じ途を選んだ
We chose the same path,
それだけだったはずなのに
that should have been all there was to it.
いつの間にかどうして
Before I knew it, why is it...
頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと
...that I want to know more about...
知りたいんだ
...the reason for the tears on my cheeks?
今更だって
Even if it's too late now,
共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
if I retrace the journey we walked together,
そこに君はいなくとも
even though you are no longer there,
きっと見つけられる
I'm sure I can find it.
物語は続く
The story continues,
一人の旅へと発つ
setting off on a solitary journey.
立ち寄る街で出会う人の
Meeting people in the towns I stop by,
記憶の中に残る君は
you, who remain in their memories,
相も変わらずお人好しで
are as soft-hearted as always,
格好つけてばかりだね
always trying to look cool, aren't you?
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは
The symbols you created here and there
勝ち取った平和の証
are proof of the peace we won.
それすら未来でいつか
Even those, so that someday in the future,
私が一人にならないように
I won't be left all alone,
あの旅を思い出せるように
and so I can remember that journey,
残された目印
are signs left behind.
まるで御伽の話
It's just like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
A testament to the end
私を変えた出会い
The encounter that changed me,
百分の一の旅路
a mere one-hundredth of my journey.
君の勇気をいつか
Someday, your courage...
風がさらって
...will be swept away by the wind,
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
and even if it fades from everyone's memory,
私が未来に連れていくから
I will carry it with me into the future.
君の手を取った
I took your hand
あの日にすべて始まった
and on that day, everything began.
くだらなくて思わず
So silly, we couldn't help...
吹き出してしまうような
...but burst out laughing.
ありふれた時間が
Those ordinary times,
今も眩しい
are still radiant even now.
知りたいんだ
I want to understand it more.
今更だって
Even if it's too late now,
振り返ればそこにはいつでも
whenever I look back, you are always...
優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
...standing there, smiling gently at me.
新たな旅の始まりは
The beginning of a new journey...
君が守り抜いたこの地に
...takes place in this land you protected,
芽吹いた命と共に
together with the newly budding lives.
「勇者」、いい曲だったね～
"Yuusha" was such a great song, wasn't it?
うん。VJとかもね。あ、VJっていうのは、この後ろのMVのことなんだけど
Yeah. And the VJ as well... Oh, by VJ, I mean the MV in the background.
VJとかもね、こだわって作ってみたので、ぜひぜひいっぱい見てもらいたいな
Since we put a lot of care into the VJ, I really hope you'll watch it many times!
アーカイブとかもね！あ、まだ終わってないけどね！
In the archives too! Ah, though we're not done yet!
ゲストさんもいっぱい来てくれて嬉しいよー！ありがとうーー！
I'm so glad so many guests could join us! Thank you so much!
あ、なんかさ、今までのセトリさ、あの平成の...
Oh, and by the way, our setlist up to now, like Heisei...
令和のアニソンとかを盛り込んでみたんだけど、
I tried incorporating some Reiwa anime songs,
知ってる曲はありましたか？
but did you know any of the songs?
お気に入りの曲とかあったかな？
I wonder if you had any favorites?
もし好きな曲が見つかったりしたら、教えてほしいなと思います。
If you found any song you like, I'd love for you to tell me.
「この曲よかったよ」とか教えてください！
Please let me know, like "this song was great!"
あ、今コメントで教えてくれてもいいんだよ。
Oh, you can even tell me in the comments right now!
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
でも！
But!
これで終わりじゃないんだよね。
This isn't the end yet!
一曲だけ、
There's one more...
この後、ちょっとゲームの曲とかも混ざってるんだけど、
After this, some game songs are mixed in,
コンセプトがあるセトリになってます、この後。
but the upcoming setlist has a certain concept.
探してみて頂けると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could try to figure it out.
ゲストさんもね、まだ出ていない人もいるので、
Some of the guests haven't appeared yet,
楽しみにしててくださーい！
so please look forward to it!
よし。
Alright.
では、聴いてください。
Now then, please listen.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding onto my unyielding wish.
海の色が紅く染まってゆく 無重力状態
The color of the sea stains crimson, in a state of zero gravity.
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this.
いつも跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've always cleared those unjumpable hurdles with a spirit that refuses to lose, but...
出し切れない実力は誰のせい？
This strength I can't fully show... whose fault is it?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding onto my unyielding wish.
色褪せない心の地図
An unfading map of my heart,
光にかざそう
I'll hold it up to the light.
どれだけ泣けば朝に出逢えるの 孤独な夜
How much do I have to cry to meet the morning in this lonely night?
初めて限界を感じた日
The day I felt my limit for the first time.
きっと恋に落ちるのは まばたきみたいな一瞬の情熱だけど
Surely falling in love is like a blink of an eye, a momentary passion, but...
愛に続く坂道で強さ覚えたい
On the slope that leads to love, I want to learn strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future,
口を閉ざし瞳を光らせてきたけれど
I kept my mouth shut and my eyes shining, but...
もっと大きな優しさが見えた
I saw a much greater kindness.
跳べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've cleared those unjumpable hurdles with a spirit that refuses to lose, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに怯えていた
Every time I stood at the starting line, I was frightened.
止まらない未来を描いて
Picturing an unstoppable future,
腕を伸ばし心を開いて
Stretching out my arms, opening my heart.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding onto my unyielding wish.
色褪せない心の地図
An unfading map of my heart,
光にかざそう
I'll hold it up to the light.
胸にこみ上げてく
Wellying up in my heart,
熱く激しいこの想い
this hot and passionate feeling.
僕らは行く 最後の戦場へ
We are headed to the final battlefield,
手を取り合い 誓い合って
holding hands and making a vow.
明日の夜明け前に
Before tomorrow's dawn,
あの宇宙へと旅立つのさ
we shall depart for that universe.
僕らが地球にいたことだけ
Just the fact that we were on Earth,
どうか覚えていて欲しいよ
please remember it.
振り向くな
Don't look back!
涙を見せるな
Don't show your tears!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
明日を取り戻すんだ
We will take back tomorrow!
WOH WOH WOH
GONG 鳴らせ!!
Ring the GONG!!
今こそ立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Now is the time to stand up, warriors of destiny!
稲妻の剣で敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemies with the sword of lightning!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel warriors dreaming of peace,
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
believe in the future we must protect and in love!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
もしも力尽きて
Even if our strength is exhausted,
闘志の刃砕けても
and the blade of our fighting spirit is shattered,
僕らは二度と戻らない
we will never return.
ともに銀河の海に散ろう
Together, let's scatter into the sea of the galaxy.
恐れるな
Don't be afraid!
誇りを捨てるな
Don't throw away your pride!
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
さぁ 迷わず行くんだ!
Now, go forward without hesitation!
WOH WOH WOH
GONG 鳴らせ!!
Ring the GONG!!
雄々しく舞い踊れ 運命の戦士よ
Dance heroically, warriors of destiny!
金色の翼で天に羽ばたけ
Flap your golden wings and soar into the heavens!
退くことを知らない 鋼の勇者よ
Steel warriors who know no retreat,
燃えたぎるソウルの命ずるままに
as dictated by your burning soul!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
WOH WOH WOH
GONG GONG GONG 鳴らせ!!
GONG, GONG, GONG, ring it!!
今こそ立ち上がれ 運命の戦士よ
Now is the time to stand up, warriors of destiny!
稲妻の剣で敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemies with the sword of lightning!
安らぎを夢見る 鋼の勇者よ
Steel warriors dreaming of peace,
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
believe in the future we must protect and in love!
永遠へ!
To eternity!
君は聴こえる？
Can you hear?
僕のこの声が
This voice of mine...
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
...was empty, swallowed up by the darkness.
もしも世界が
If the world...
意味を持つのなら
...has any meaning,
こんな気持ちも
then even these feelings...
無駄ではない？
...aren't in vain, right?
憧れに押しつぶされて
Crushed by my own yearning,
あきらめてたんだ
I had given up.
果てしない空の色も
Without even knowing...
知らないで
...the color of the endless sky.
走り出した
I started running...
想いが今でも
...and these thoughts, even now,
この胸を確かに
are definitely...
叩いてるから
...beating inside my chest.
今日の僕が
Because today's me...
その先に続く
...connects to the future,
僕らなりの明日を
we will build...
築いていく
...our own tomorrow.
答えはそう
Yes, the answer...
いつもここにある
...is always right here.
過ぎた季節を
There's no time...
嘆く暇はない
...to grieve for seasons past.
二度と迷って
So that I...
しまわぬように
...never lose my way again.
数えきれない
Countless...
ほんのささやかな
...and slight...
そんな後悔
...regrets like those,
抱えたまま
I hold them close.
その背中だけ追いかけて
Just chasing after that back,
ここまで来たんだ
I have come this far.
探していた
I was searching...
僕だけにできること
...for something only I can do.
あの日くれた
The words you gave me that day...
言葉が今でも
...even now,
この胸に確かに
are definitely...
届いてるから
...reaching my heart.
昨日よりも
More than yesterday,
今日僕は僕の
today I am...
生まれてきた
...becoming aware...
理由に気付いていく
...of the reason I was born.
答えはそう
Yes, the answer...
いつもここにある
...is always right here.
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Go! Go! Go! Go!
だいぶ楽しいね！
This is so much fun!
はい！はい！はい！もっと！
Go! Go! Go! More!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
全てがまるで
Everything felt...
当たり前みたいだった
...as if it were completely natural.
尊い日々はまだ終わらない
These precious days aren't over yet,
そしてまた
and so, once again...
走り出した
I started running...
想いが今でも
...and these thoughts, even now,
この胸を確かに
are definitely...
叩いてるから
...beating inside my chest.
今日の僕が
Because today's me...
その先に続く
...connects to the future,
僕らなりの明日を
we will build...
築いていく
...our own tomorrow.
答えはそう
Yes, the answer...
いつもここにある
...is always right here.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ぎりわるロボ、かっこよかった？
Was the Giriwaru Robo cool?
ロボット乗って登場しちゃったよー！
I actually made my entrance riding a robot!
すごーい！かっこよかったよねー！
Incredible! It was so cool, right?
いや、この3曲はロボットの曲をテーマに
Well, these three songs were performed with...
歌って踊らせていただきました！
...a robot theme in mind!
さらにゲストもね、たくさん出演してくれて本当にありがとう！嬉しい！
Also, we had so many guests join us. Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
はい！ありがとうございます！感謝です！
Yes! Thank you very much! I'm so grateful!
あ！そういえば、この頃、この頃、みんな気づいたかな？
Oh! By the way, lately... lately, did everyone notice?
この頃、最初から実はそうだったんだけど、あの、小顔ローラーを頑張りまして、
Actually, it's been like this from the start, but, you see, I've been working hard with a face roller,
実はわため、小顔になったんですよね。こう見えて。
and Watame actually got a smaller face! Despite how I look.
もうあれだね、「顔でかい」って言われなくなっちゃうな、みんな。めんご、めんご！
So now, you won't be able to call me "big-faced" anymore, everyone. Sorry, sorry!
「そんな変わってない」って言うんじゃない！
Don't say "It hasn't changed that much!"
言うんじゃない！ちゃんと小さくなったんだな！
Don't say that! It really did get smaller!
あ、このあとね、メンバー限定の3Dライブも22時15分からわためチャンネルでやりますので、
Oh, after this, we'll also have a members-only 3D live stream starting at 22:15 on Watame's channel...
他の衣装のね、この小顔のわためも見てほしいなと思います。
...so I'd love for you to see this small-faced Watame in other outfits too.
歌って踊りますのでぜひ！22時15分、メンバーシップに入ってお待ちください！
I'll be singing and dancing, so please join the membership and wait for 22:15!
でも！まだライブも終わりではありません。
But! This live stream is not over yet.
ここで告知があります！
I have an announcement to make here!
角巻わための新曲…「ビリ」！なんと発表いたします！
I'm announcing... Tsunomaki Watame's new song, "Biri"!
えー、このあと22時からMVが投稿されて、
The music video will be posted after this at 22:00,
で、楽曲配信が24時から始まります！よろしくお願いします！
and the song distribution will start at 24:00! Please look forward to it!
えー、神田ジョンさん、堀江晶太さん、DECO*27さんという布陣で作った、
We made this with an amazing lineup: Kanda John-san, Horie Shota-san, and DECO*27-san!
わための、こう、新しい部分だったりとか、
It shows a new side of Watame,
ま、ちょっと、あんまり歌ったことないような感じの曲になっているかなと思っているんで、ぜひ楽しみにしていてください。
and it's a song unlike anything I've sung before, so please look forward to it.
あ、でも？あ、でもこのあと、
But wait? After this,
まだ1曲ぐらい、やる時間があるか。
do we still have time to perform one more song?
ああ、ああ、じゃあ、
Ah, ah, then...
「ビリ」やろっか？
shall we perform "Biri"?
え、あと1曲、新曲「ビリ」！ぜひみんなに聴いていただきたいなと思うので、最後まで、
Yes, one more song, my new song "Biri"! I want everyone to hear it, so please stay until the end.
あの、ダンスも可愛いんでね、ちょっと一生懸命踊ります。見てください！
The dance is also very cute, so I'll do my best. Please watch!
では、最後の曲、聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the last song.
「ビリ」。
"Biri."
選択肢をくだだだだ　もうハイ or ローでぐちゃぐちゃ闘志
Choices are all messed up, and it's a messy fight between high and low
合唱ネガ and ポジ　一回舞うわ　なんてこったい感
A chorus of negatives and positives, let's dance once, what a mess of a feeling
美 美 美 な
Bi-bi-bi-beautiful
ややや、やるだけやるしかない　もう
Ye-ye-ye-yeah, there's nothing to do but do it, now
ちっちぇいことでへこんでらんない
I can't be getting depressed over small things
胃圧するまで育つだけさ
Growing until my stomach feels pressurized
心配いらずのジェットコースター
A worry-free roller coaster
いけいけ
Go, go!
研ぎ澄ました脳でおめかしさぞかしハッピーでいっぱい
Dressing up with a sharpened mind, surely full of happiness
いりいりチャンス　注ぎ込んだ願いが香り立つ　今僕になるんだ
Iri-iri chance! The poured-in wishes smell sweet, now I'm becoming myself
僕しかできないこと認めてほしいの
I want you to acknowledge what only I can do
「どうせ」とか思ってらんないわ
I can't afford to think things like "anyway..."
だっせ　妄言ばこん！切り刻んでいこう
So lame! Slay those delusions and chop them up!
まだ一等賞まで放電がありそう
It seems there's still electricity discharge before reaching first place
当選しちゃう？かは挑戦次第
Will I win? That depends on my challenge
オーケーやるかやらないかだ
Okay, it's just a matter of whether you do it or not
「はぁめんどっぽい」　「これでエンドっぽい」　叩き潰した弱音がちょー痛い
"Ah, seems troublesome", "This seems like the end", the crushed weakness hurts so much!
夢が叶っちゃって甘くなれ
My dream came true, so become sweet
黙れ　完璧はノーノーノー　グッドバイ
Shut up, perfection is a no-no-no, goodbye!
美 美 美 な
Bi-bi-bi-beautiful
昨今やることやるだけバッドもう
Doing what needs to be done lately is just bad, already
涙腺アミダ全泣きが確定
My tear ducts are like a lottery, crying is guaranteed
同情求めてはわわわわねえ
Seeking sympathy, oh my god, hey
ちゃんと抱きしめてえっとえっと…
Hold me tight, um, let me see...
にげにげ
Run, run!
顔出した絶望でごまかし乗る歌詞ハッピーが足んない
With despair showing its face, getting by on deceptive lyrics, not enough happiness
にげにげチャンス
Run-run chance!
あたしを愛せない比べたら　比べるだけ負け犬（ルーザー）
I can't love myself, if I compare, comparing only makes me a loser
ありなし選べちゃうけど弱気になるかも
I can choose yes or no, but I might get timid
「どうせ無理」と思って仕舞っちゃうわ
I'll end up locking myself away thinking "it's impossible anyway"
だっせ　有言だもん！叶わないもん
So lame! I said it out loud, but it won't come true!
また一等賞指くわえて見てるの
Looking at first place again with envy
あたしじゃない誰かだったの
It wasn't me, it was someone else
ノーノー誰か倒れてよ
No, no, someone please fall!
ぜーので勘違いの未来（いやいや無理だって）
On the count of three, a misunderstood future (No way, it's impossible)
前進もっとハイになって（あー厳しい）
Move forward, get higher (Ah, that's tough)
贅沢夢見していたい
I want to dream luxuriously
息ができない
I can't breathe!
ローさん黙ってね？
Lowe-san, please shut up?
わぁ　わぁ　わぁ
Wah, wah, wah
全部見透かされてるみたいじゃん
It feels like everything is seen right through us
はぁ？
Huh?
ハイさんアツアツのブレーキ
Hi-san, the brake is boiling hot
ブレーキ　ブレーキ　アクセル！
Brake, brake, accelerator!
噛み合わないね　笑えるくらい
We're out of sync, it's almost funny
それならこのまま行くしかないか
If that's the case, we have no choice but to go like this
役割分担　それのがいいか
Dividing roles, maybe that's better
大丈夫！
It's alright!
無理！無理！
No way! No way!
重ねて
Layer them on
僕しか会えない子と
With the girl only I can meet,
仲良くしてるの
I'm getting along well with her
どうせならかましてみちゃいますか保存
Since we're at it, shall we blow them away?
妄言ばかり保存
All these wild delusions,
切り刻んでいこう
let's slice them all up
また一等賞
First place once again
指くわえて見ててよ
Just watch with envy!
誰かじゃない
It's not just anyone,
僕がいいんだよ
I'm the one who should do it!
オッケー
Okay
わたしも奏でるんだ
I'll play along too
前線突破
Breaking through the front lines
溢れ出せば
Once it overflows,
こすり倒した美学で
with our thoroughly polished aesthetic...
しゃぶりたい
...I want to savor it all
夢が叶ったって
Even if dreams come true,
もともとねえ
there's nothing there to begin with
黙れ　黙れ
Shut up, shut up
不完全は
Imperfection is...
ノー　ノー　ノー　ノー　ノー　ノー
...no, no, no, no, no, no!
グッバイ
Goodbye!
ビビビなビリビリ
B-B-B-na Biri-Biri
みんなー！角巻わため生誕祭2025『アニソン NIGHT FEVER!』
Everyone! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2025 "Anisong Night Fever!"
楽しんでいただけましたでしょうかー！
Did you all enjoy it?!
ここからは告知がありますので、もう少しお付き合いお願いします！
We have some announcements from here, so please stick with me for a bit longer!
まず！さっきも告知させていただきましたが、このあと10時に
First! As I announced earlier, at 10 PM...
わためちゃんねるにて角巻わための新曲『ビリ』のMVが公開されます！
...the MV for Tsunomaki Watame's new song "Biri" will be released on Watame Channel!
チャンネルはそのままでお願いします！
Please stay tuned to this channel!
そして！24時から『ビリ』の楽曲配信も始まりますので、
And! The digital distribution of "Biri" will start at midnight,
ぜひ3rdライブを実現させるためにも、買っていただけると嬉しいです！
so I'd be really happy if you could buy it to help make the 3rd live concert happen!
さらに！このあと10時から角巻わため誕生日記念2025のグッズが発売開始になります！
Furthermore! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2025 merchandise will go on sale from 10 PM!
フルセットはこんな感じ！
The full set looks like this!
なんですが、ひとつずつ紹介したいと思います！
But let me introduce them one by one!
まず！ふーみママ描き下ろしのTシャツ！
First, the T-shirt illustrated by Fumi-mama!
正面はポケットから出てる風の絵わためがいます。
On the front, there's a picture of Watame peeking out of a pocket.
背面には「よぉ！」って感じで挨拶してるわためがいるので、
On the back, there's Watame waving "Yo!" to greet people,
後ろの人から見ても楽しめるTシャツとなっております！
making it a fun shirt even for people looking from behind!
そして！わためいとジャージ！わための制服衣装とお揃い
And, the Watamate Jersey! It's in matching colors with Watame's school uniform,
色違いの黄色いジャージになってまして、
but in a different shade of yellow!
背面にはわためが描き下ろした『わためいとエアーギター』がプリントされております！
And the back features a "Watamate Air Guitar" print illustrated by Watame!
さらに！ぬいぐるみキーホルダー制服ジャージ衣装バージョン！
Next, the Plushie Keyring (School Uniform Jersey Costume Ver.)!
これがもうめちゃくちゃ可愛い！
This is just so incredibly cute!
お出かけにも連れて行きやすいサイズのぬいぐるみです。
It's a plushie that's perfect for taking along on outings.
ぜひ色んな所に連れて行って、はばないしてください！
Please take it to various places and have a nice day (habanice)!
そしてラスト！MACCO先生描き下ろしの缶バッジ4種セット！
And finally, the 4-Can Badge Set illustrated by MACCO-sensei!
どのわためも可愛いので、ぜひ推し活などに使ってください！
Every Watame is cute, so please use them for your fan activities!
こちらのフルセットをご購入していただいた方には、
For those who purchase this full set,
角巻わためのショートボイスセットと、チェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
a short voice set and a polaroid-style bromide card are included!
ボイスはなんと！15種類！
And the voice tracks are... believe it or not, 15 types!
チェキ風ブロマイドカードには、直筆サイン＆メッセージを購入した方全員に書かせていただきます！
I will write my handwritten signature and message on the bromide card for everyone who buys it!
さらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
In addition, as a full set bonus for the talent premium goods,
去年から発売された『hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME』で使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
you get one card for the "hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME" which launched last year!
このカードは、ホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
This card is only available to those who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典に付くのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード、
The bonus card is a key card to show off your favorite,
推しホロメンバーカードです！カードの詳細や遊び方については、公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
an Oshi Holo Member Card! Check the official website for card details and how to play!
とっても盛りだくさんな最強グッズなので、ぜひたくさん買っていただけると嬉しいです！
It's an ultimate goods lineup packed with so many things, so I hope you get plenty of them!
そして！このあと10時15分からは、
And! From 10:15 PM tonight,
メン限3Dライブがありますので、ビリのMVを見て、グッズをチェックして、見に来てください！
there will be a membership-only 3D live stream. Check out the MV and goods, and come watch!
メン限ライブでは、温度差で風邪をひく可能性が……
In the membership-only live stream, you might catch a cold due to the temperature difference...
みんなのこと待ってるねー！
I'll be waiting for you all!
「アニソン Night Fever!! 角巻わため生誕祭 2025」メンバーシップ限定 アンコールライブ!!
[Anisong Night Fever!! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2025: Membership-Only Encore Live!!]